Joshua Wootonn

Fullstack Engineer with a knack for User Experience

github.com/joshuawootonn-joshuawootonn@gmail.com-joshuawootonn.com

In the past 8 months, I created a living mock that disrupted a 3-year-old production app, took that mock to production in hospitals across the Midwest, and got reviews from our CS department such as "This is going to make the MAs' jobs so much more efficient and impact so many patients living with diabetes! Kudos!"

I have also delivered production products with Qt and Electron as a freelance developer and worked as a freelance web designer.

I love working on emerging products and delighting users, and I am looking for an opportunity to do just that.

Experience

Fullstack Engineer / Digital Diagnostics

SEP 2017 - OCT 2020

- > Created a React web app to replace the Windows Forms version IDx-DR. It was off the books at first, but soon gained steam and became the flagship product
- > Iterated designs in Figma, implemented designs in Electron/React, and tested implementation in Cypress / Spectron
- > Played a pivotal role in features like image snapshot testing, end to end testing, dark mode, interactive animation, and product analytics
- > Mentored three engineers, who were new to React, Electron, and Cypress, spreading the ownership of the product among a backend heavy team

Freelance Software Engineer / All American Concrete

MAR 2016 - JUNE 2020

- > Created a labor tracking app called Time Track that facilitates 60 employees to track work, 3 estimators to view analytics, and 1 secretary to automate payroll
- > Developed an initial version with Qt / C++ / MySql that was used from 2016 to 2018
- > Migrated old version to use Electron / React / Node / MySql enabling better analytics, sleeker UI, and more intuitive UX

Software Engineer / Graze Analytics

JAN 2019 - SEP 2019

- > Designed a product that allowed users to pay for their meal without interacting with a waiter
- > Created a React app to collect payment through Stripe and feedback through an Ant Design based form
- > Developed a Node / MySql backend for coordinating Stripe and Omnivore transactions, while storing analytics data for restaurants

Education

University of Iowa / Computer Science and Engineering

GRADUATION: May 2019 - GPA: 3.54

Skills

Languages: ES7+ JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, C++, Java, Ruby

Technologies: React, DOM API, Electron, Gatsby.js, Next.js, Storybook, Canvas, WebGL, Three.js, MySql, Postgres, Node.js, ASP.NET Core, Docker, Git, Git Flow, GraphQL, HTML, CSS

Tools: Github, Azure DevOps, Figma, Illustrator